ADEEB HASSAN

Django Developer

+92 329 4457925 | adeebhassi@gmail.com | github/adeebhassi | linkedin/adeeb-hassan

Objective

Full Stack Django Developer focused on building easy-to-use applications. Excited to use my skills in Django, RESTful APIs, and responsive design to create smooth and engaging online experiences. I am dedicated to continuous learning and staying updated with the latest technologies to improve my skills and deliver innovative solutions.

Skills

- HTML
- CSS
- JAVASCRIPT
- Bootstrap
- React
- Django

- Django REST Framework
- Django Admin Customization
- Object Relational Mapping(ORM)
- SQL, NoSQL Database
- Web Scraping
- Git / GitHub

Experience

Full Stack Developer | Maaz Informatics

July 2024 - Present

- Currently working with Django Rest Framework to develop and maintain backend services.
- Designing React-based frontend to enhance user experience and functionality.
- Collaborating with the development team on project requirements and implementation

React Developer (Remote) | ALPHA Solutions

December 2024-Present

• Developing responsive website frontend in React and integrating it with backend to ensure seamless functionality and user experience.

Projects

E-MART

A feature-rich e-commerce platform built using Django, offering customers a seamless shopping experience and providing the business with powerful management and analytical capabilities.

- Product Catalog Management
- Shopping Cart and Checkout
- Order Management
- Payment Gateway Integration

- Customer Accounts and Profiles
- Promotions and Discounts
- Inventory and Stock Management
- Analytics and Reporting

RTNS Management Portal

A Django-powered web application that I developed as my university's final year project to streamline the end-to-end management of events, content, and submission for the RTNS event.

- User registration with email verification
- Content Management

- Certificate generating for speakers
- Email notifications for abstract approval/rejection

Education

BS Information Technology

University of Education, Lahore

FSc pre Engineering

Inspire Group of College

2020-2024

CGPA: 3.49/4.00

2018-2020

Marks: 77%